# **Catie Tortorella**

# Software Developer & UI/UX Designer









### Summary

Software Developer & Designer with a passion for clear and effective reusable code using proven UI/UX methods based on research. Detailed problem solver utilizing knowledge of current UI/UX and usability standards to create technology that is easy for humans to use.

### Experience

#### UI Developer & UI/UX Designer

Hookit Sponsorship Analytics & Valuation 5/2018 - 3/2020 San Diego, CA

- Sole developer of the company's first React/Redux application, Pro Account -a tool for professional athletes and influencers to see their effectiveness at promoting their brands on social media platforms.
- Coded monthly and transactional HTML emails from Sketch files
- Developed code for email share feature within reports in ASP.Net application
- Implemented responsive styling into existing ASP.Net application
- Created UI/UX design for user management permissions
- Collaborated with engineering and product management teams on technical specifications for design
- Took on the role of sole product designer at Hookit. Collaborating closely with engineering and product managers, getting buy-ins from the executive team, creating mocks in Sketch, and prototyping quickly in Framer X and InVision
- Created UI designs for various analytical reports within the ASP.Net application
- Maintained company design style guide
- Created an API using C# to access JSON data from Mandrill API to save email open and click data to SQL database.

#### Web Developer

**DoWhop** 2/2018 - 3/2018 San Diego, CA

- Built user profile image upload and display feature using JavaScript and Firebase cloud functions
- Using SendGrid API built automated email feature using Firebase cloud functions
- Provided usability review of current site and implemented bug fixes
- Analyzed legacy code within React application and made improvements to code architecture
- Assisted with logistics of co-sponsored networking and promotion event

#### **Executive Assistant**

Middleton Team Inc. 4/2015 - 10/2017 La Jolla, CA

- Created marketing materials for home listings to distribute using print and web
- Responsible for social media outreach and networking for listings.
- Supported clients and agents in the home buying and selling process; generated
  \$172 Million in sales over 2.5 years
- Created and maintained single page websites for highend listings.

## Technologies

#### **Front End**

Javascript BootStrap

HTML/CSS React Native

React jQuery Redux .Net

Sass C3.js

#### **Testing**

Testing Library Jest

#### **Back End**

Express.js Node.js

REST APIS C#

JSON SQL

#### **Software & Processes**

Git Agile/SCRUM

**Email Development** 

Sketch Framer X

InVision Adobe Photoshop

Jira Confluence

### Education

#### Web Development Bootcamp

#### **Learn Academy**

2017 San Diego, CA

#### **BA in Communications**

#### **University of Massachusetts Amherst**

2009 Amherst, MA